Turn it around for me
Anyone
Even unto a demon!
If only you died, you'd survive.
I'm gambling for fuck's sake!
Akagi
Akagi Shigeru
ron
Son of a bitch.
Make sure this is the last time.
At any rate, you've only played Mahjong for a few hours.
Except you didn't deal into anyone's hand even once.
Call for Yagi
Ah. Even a cop.
So, at last the pro arrives.
Ryuzaki, having a hard time?
ron
It's beyond question.
Ryuzaki is simply no match for him.
The only concern now is this man
Yagi Keiji
Ryuzaki
Certainly, we're 23,00 points behind
and it's already South hand 2.
and...?
Heh. Turning the game around at this point.
I'll have to overextend quite a bit.
Observing him for the rest of this East-South match is safest.
Observe!?
Why Yagi?
They say the kid's a beginner.
That makes him even more eerie as an unknown quantity.
It's best to not underestimate him.
o-okay
This man.
Did he pick up on Akagi's talent with one glance?
And what's more simply observing is more frightening.
Most people would want to show off in a situation like this.
His restraint is admirable.
He's in a different league than Ryuzaki.
Yagi Keiji
With Yagi observing,
he aims to find the way Akagi has taken first place.
H-how did he sense that the previous player's Tenpai?
JyunChan SanSyoku
A middle 8 wait.
Normally he would discard an 8 Sou
Why therefore discard that other tile?
Both Chanta hands and these discards are tough to read.
It's more likely he'd think he'd deal into that hand
with the 5 Sou rather than the 8 Sou.
How?
How can he trust his reads to this extent?
Just what is this kid seeing?
He's looking at it.
The three zones.
The left hand player's discards can be separated into three zones.
In these discards, the 6 Pin and 6 Man tiles
and the 3/2 Sou were discarded before the 3 Pin and 9 Sou.
and therefore, the 3 Pin and 9 Sou were more important.
And this vicinity is a danger zone.
And if we then go into reading the hand itself...
The first 6 Pin discard removes the possibility of a Metanpin hand.
And thus he holds a Chanta hand.
And furthermore if you consider his discard of the 3 and 2 Sou
a 7 8 9 SanSyoku remains in his hand
And in that case the North, 3 Sou and 2 Sou were unnecessary.
But if it's a Chanta hand, the 5 Man discarded on the 5th turn
would suggest this had.
A slim possibility remains
delaying the discard of the 5 Man.
In the end the left hand opponent's hand should look like this:
This kid has seen through this up to now.
Not only does he seem to see through everyone's hands,
He has incredible luck!
The left hand player is in a position to simply crush Akagi.
Tenpai!
Riitchi
This Richi off a 6 Pin discard...
This is a mistake!
Here the 4 Pin closed triplet is 100% profitable.
He may happen to draw another 4 Pin.
and achieve a Kan.
And thus there's the chance of an additional Dora tile.
And if you think about it, declaring Riichi with instead a 5 Pin discard...
you get this hand. Infinitely better!
Why on earth didn't he do that?
That's it! Of course!
He's making mistakes characteristic of a beginner.
I can beat him.
I'll take advantage of that opening and destroy his game.
Once he's off balance...
He's vunerable to a more able player.
Hmm. Why's he smiling?
My god.
Has the bastard found a weakness?
Ron.
Riichi Ippatsu TanYao
Five thousand two hundred points.
Well done! First place.
I'll take your place, Ryuzaki.
p-please, Yagi.
#/tv/shows subbing cartel and japanimation enthusiast club
presents:
A
K
G
I
rootB
as
Akagi
soapkills
as
Nangou
swarm
as
Yasuoka
ptg
as
Ryuzaki
Keret
as
Yagi
confuse
as
Ichikawa
Episode 2
* Reminder that soy milk and other soy based products contain high amounts of estrogen, known to cause impotence and feminine body traits amoung men ages 12-24. Please see your doctor for further information.*
One more game.
If you take first in one more game.
My debts are entirely repaid.
You're alright.
Ryuzaki.
I have a little proposal.
hunh?
This Yagi guy
He knows all sorts of tricks and slight of hand, doesn't he.
So therefore
When tiles are collected, and everyone stacks theirs,
Yagi should stack afterwards from the remaining tiles.
To protect against any cheating...
This is the very least we could ask for.
HA HA HA HA
Yasuoka, dude.
I heard this kid cheated from the start.
How about
We make a little deal.
A deal?
Mutually
If anyone is found cheating
They lose an arm.
Okay. As you like.
Okay.
W-wait
And one further thing.
I have a request for you specifically.
This contest
It's a little unfair, don't you think?
Unfair?
Ryuzaki is apt to lose a huge sum of money.
And as his rep player, my name is at stake.
I could lose my livelihood.
What do you have to compare with that?
If you lose, only Nangou will be in trouble.
You won't lose anything at all.
Exactly.
Well, you see,
Our conditions are too different from the start.
What are you getting at?
It's simple. Let's make a personal wager.
100,000 Yen for each East-South match.
100,000!?!
I realize that you can't get that kid of money right now.
That's why I'm willing to accept a substitute for it.
A substitute?
One finger for 100,000 Yen.
Now, just wait a minute!
You're playing a kid!
How about it?
Is it a deal?
Okay. If it's the same.
Hunh?
We know I can't pay that huge sum.
But, you look a little suspicious.
If you're not able to pay
you substitute a finger a well.
If we say that...
How about it?
Of course I agree.
T-this is crazy!
That bastard's a top player.
He's bluffing.
It can't be helped if he's a kid or not.
They tried to scare him and see what he'd do.
The plan was to overwhelm him with pressure.
I see...
The little bastard.
He parried the Yakuza's threats elegantly.
He's got some balls.
Gambling changes fundamentally depending on whether you have something to lose
When there's nothing to lose...
or if there's nothing to gain,
only one's intuition and guts are the deciding factors.
Ability is paramount.
However if there is a large sum, or life at stake...
you cannot win by ability alone.
No matter how well you read your opponent.
It's meaningless if  you don't trust your own conclusions
You must entrust your fate to your decisions.
Which means your will to trust yourself
Your soul itself is what is being tested.
Riichi.
Yagi.
He's already bluffing.
A closed wait for a 7 Sou.
With a hand like that
you'd usually wait for a two sided wait before declaring Riichi.
Bastard. He wants to see how Akagi will react.
Of course. Now this is interesting.
Right now, If I were Akagi, i'd think...
The 2nd turn discard of the 7 Man creates a safe zone,
suggesting a 6 Man discard.
However, if you're more faint of heart,
The 9 Sou safe tile discard is also a possibility.
But Akagi is Akagi.
And this is no normal war of nerves.
He made the 6 Man pass
But holds onto the wining tile, the 7 Sou.
And even under this pressue
He trusts his decisions, and never wavers.
The 5 Man tile also passes
Seizing the game flow, this West first round belongs to Akagi.
At last!
* An Agari Hai is a tile that, upon discard, sets up your hand to win. It "tells" what your hand is waiting on.
That 7 Sou is unmistakably an Agari-hai.*
Yagi's tenacity is obvious.
Even if he loses dealer position
He defies Akagi's reading of his hand.
What can you do, Akagi?
I don't need to win this trash hand.
You may take the East hand one
But in return you'll pick up some doubts.
And those doubts in time
Will hit you hard, like a body blow.
Once you start questioning your own judgement
You will seriously doubt yourself towards the end
When the pressure's on.
Then he's very likely to make a bad discard.
And that mistake
Can be fatal in a match like this.
キターーー(゜∀゜)ーーーー!!!!!
RyanPeiKou Pinhu Tsumo
A Mangan hand.
T-that's strange.
It wouldn't be odd for him to be waiting for that tile.
Could he...?
Tenpai
PRICK
He threw away a Mangan win.
to confirm his own reads were correct?
This is Mahjong game that could cost the loser a finger.
This kid. Doesn't he care what happens to him?
Yagi.
Would you show me your hand?
You're in Tenpai, aren't you?
Just as I thought.
A twisted way of playing.
Typical of someone who only ever thinks of tricking people.
So unimaginative.
Yagi. You alright?
Don't you worry about me.
The game has only just begun.
???????
I can't gauge this kid's strength.
Without doubt this man
will soon become an absurdly good player.
However,
But, right now I can beat him.
I have grasped your weakness.
And that is
He doesn't understand how Kan and Riichi really work.
That IGNORANCE
Earlier...
Riichi.
You declared Riichi by discarding the 6 Pin.
But at that moment if you discarded the 5 Pin instead
The 4 Pin closed triplet is 100% better positioned.
In time if you draw another 4 Pin you may declare closed Kan.
And in Kan there is the possibility of another Dora.
But why didn't he do that?
I dare say you thought you can't declare Kan during Riichi.
It's a misunderstanding indicative of beginners.
Your ignorance in declaring Kan during Riichi is that very thing.
That awesome Yaku called Riichi.
Now I will teach it to you!
In East hand 2,
And it ends without a winner.
Then, Akagi is first to seize the game flow.
Tsumo.
White Yakuhai. 400/700 points. Honba count 2.
Riichi.
Tsumo.
Riichi, Tsumo
Nomi*. 700/1,300 points.
*Nomi: the state of a hand which contains only yaku and no dora.
Even if some common people are able to grasp the game flow,
they often can't take advantage of it.
Riichi.
And if the rate of game play becomes too great,
they become unnecessarily cautious.
He breaks his own flow.
しかし
Akagi has no such limitations.
Tsumo.
Mentanpin, Tsumo.
One Dora. A Mangan win.
2,000/4,000 points.
From the very start he's steadfast beyond imagination.
His hands move without hesitation.
Riichi.
Riichi
Ron.
Riichi. Ippatsu. IttsuKan.
And dealer payment. 12,000 points.
At the end of South round 2, Akagi comes top.
plus 27.
Yagi is second with minus 3.
Yagi hasn't yet made his move.
He's lost more points than he can,
so he uses a skillful trick.
This is the hand I've been waiting for!
This is the cheat known as the "Caterpillar"
And under it, Yagi's hand will undergo a Metamorphosis.
First, he takes two 7 Sou tiles in his left hand.
And pretending to push his own wall forward,
He pushes the 7 Sou tiles into the wall.
The tiles basically mimic the motion of a caterpillar.
His final move is to return two tiles from the right edge in his right hand.
Practiced many tens of thousands of times,
there is no hesitation.
It helps that, at this point, everyone is focused on sorting their own tiles.
In Yagi's hand movements, there is nothing to remember.
Done like this, the two tiles returned to his hand,
merely ensure he has the correct number of tiles.
What's important are the two he has placed in the wall.
One is the Dora indicator,
And the other will be one in time.
In this way, his garbage hand
can transform into a monster hand with EIGHT dora.
Riichi
GOT HIM
When he knows he won't deal into anyone's hand,
and can draw his winning tile he declares Riichi, even with a large lead.
His reading is probably correct.
He has an innate sense for that.
SHIKASHI, even this genius has a weak point.
They don't number many,
He doesn't have enough experience in Mahjong rough play.
And moreover,
He doesn't know the terror of the Riichi!
I'm going to teach him.
The Achilles Heel of the Riichi.
But first, Akagi,
We force you out so you can't draw your Tsumo.
Pon.
The game flow don't mean shit if you can't draw a tile.
And now,
At last, it's all in place.
Sorry.
Yagi, you bastard.
Just what are you planning?
Pon.
GOT HIM!!!!!!
Kan!
F-four Dora.
E-EIGHT DORA
Riichi
Now do you understand the terror of the Riichi?
Once you're declared Riichi, you're powerless to adapt
to any changes that may come later.
So this is what he was aiming for?
He doesn't know the terror of the Yaku called "Riichi."
A weakness characteristic of a novice.
Chi
So.
That 3 Pin is my winning tile.
But you are powerless.
You MUST discard it.
Rooooooohhhhnnn.
There are no ura-Dora, but 8 Dora, Riichi.
A Baiman win, no?
A 16,000 point direct hit.
Turns the game around!
A-akagi?
Yagi.
I'm going to be more direct now.
Akagi vs. Yagi.
At last the confrontation reaches its final act.
Yagi with a 3,700 point lead,
and Akagi playing catchup after a reversal.
There's only one hand left, South hand 4.
He's got a slow hand.
Has the potential for merely a Chinitsu.
But that's not what he needs.
Here, a Tanpin would be best.
Yagi's good with only a 1,000 point win.
Now you've got to keep pace with this bastard's speed.
But at that moment,
the young genius
imagined an entirely different story based on this hand.
Pon.
Chi.
I see. Agaki you little scamp.
Akagi's trying to head Yagi off.
He's trying to make them think he's going for a Chinitsu or Honitsu hand.
and tying the hands of the other players besides Yagi.
In this showdown,
they don't have the balls to stay in the game,
and risk dealing him a winning tile in the last hand.
After he called tiles twice, they're only discarding safe tiles.
They're out.
Pon.
It looks like a Chinitsu hand, but there's no way.
but now he doesn't need that big of a hand.
Those three calls are probably bluffs instead.
More likely he's got a Tanyao.
With a single dora tile, he'll overtake my 4,000 point lead.
And if that's the case,
I , above all, can't discard this.
Calling tiles three times,
He's almost certainly in Tenpai.
If I delay, he has time to draw his winning tile.
Damn. He hasn't realized Akagi's not in Tenpai.
If anything, I think this is on purpose.
Right now, the North tile Akagi discarded,
it's a hell wait since two North tiles have been discarded.
However, in this situation,
but still, no one will take the chance of discarding one.
Most likely, what Akagi is aiming at,
is a 3-way wait on 3 or 6 Man.
Nevertheless,
These remaining 4 Man tiles are damn strange.
Is there some other goal here?
Kan.
Why on earth did he declare Kan?
Forcing yourself to wait on a single tile
instead of waiting on 3 is a mistake.
He's put his own head in a noose.
I can't fucking believe it.
Now he's done it.
Letting your hand slip while drawing a Rinshan Tile.
That settles it.
He's without mistake in a naked wait for a Man tile.
That is to say,
At least, this turn,
any tile but a Man tile is safe to discard!
Even an extremely dangerous Dora tile, the 4 Sou.
Why does he have such a calm demeanor?
And above all, why did he declare Kan?
Is there some reason why he threw away a 3 way wait for a single naked wait?
The 4 Sou Dora? But I'm sure I saw...
I see.
That 4 Man Kan was just a trick.
From Yagi's perspective it would look like a normal Kan.
But to Akagi,
The 4 Sou Dora was hidden in the closed 4 Man Kan, like so.
When he drew his Rinshan replacement tile,
He deliberately knocked over his own tile.
and let his opponent see only the Man symbol.
That is to say, he made his opponent mistakenly believe he's in a single Man tile wait.
This turn that Dora
would be impossible to discard because Akagi is going for a Tanyao hand.
It's an utterly dangerous tile!
However, in this turn only...
What's the matter?
You realized your own mistake?
You're such an Idiot, Yagi-san.
Did you really believe in a match like this,
I would knock over my own tile?
You shouldn't trust people so...
Ron.
TanYao with Two Dora.
A reversal.
Y-YAGI
I'm SAVED.
Akagi. Thank you.
Really. Because of you. I'm saved.
And I'll never gamble again!
Ryuzaki-san. This isn't over yet.
Let's take the 3 million that erased Nangou's debt
and play one more match with that at stake.
Double or nothing.
Akagi, don't be reckless!
If you lose, it's my life on the line!
Nangou-san.
You've already faced death once.
Let's push this to the limit.
You're talking nonsense.
Nevertheless,
they're the ones feeling the most pressure at a double or nothing proposal.
The fact that they've got no hopes of winning this game
Is what they're feeling most of all.
You'll never see such sitting ducks again.
If you can pluck them, pluck them.
I wish I never set eyes on this kid (???)
Okay.
Detective! Just a moment.
The hell you want!?
I-it won't open!
The hell is this about?!?
Detective.
Please, stop him.
Hunh?
It's enough that my life has been saved.
Just please stop him for me already.
He can't be stopped.
Detective,
He's the "chicken run" survivor.
He's not really my nephew!
I know all about that.
If that's the case then why?
I wanted to see him play Mahjong a bit more.
To begin with, in a Chicken Run contest,
You understand why people can't do it, don't you?
No idea.
It's a contest on a sea cliff.
Those who can do it, go off the cliff.
Therefore, don't rashly apply the brakes.
Done cleanly the probability of survival is high.
T-then he...?
He didn't brake at all.
But if that's the case, he had no hope of escape.
In that case, the little bastard made that decision, and put his heart and soul into it.
Tonight I confirmed it by watching that kid's Mahjong.
At whatever moment,
I've observed his ability to make trustworthy decisions
with an unwavering heart.
The ability to trust one's own decisions,
That's him to a T. Akagi Shigeru.
No, Detective. Just wait a..
It's begun.
Weak men unavoidably will fall apart.
Akagi knows this instinctively.
Riichi.
Ron.
Riichi, Ippatsu, Chitoitsu, Ura Dora.
Riichi.
If I discard the 3 Man or 6 Man I'm in Tenpai,
It's a little risky, though.
I-f I stop...
T-this is...
I wasn't expecting to see that.
Ron.
Riichi, Ippatsu, 3 Dora
You look dizzy, Yagi.
Impossible!
He drew and discarded that 2 Man when he declared Riichi
And even though I defended against it above all (???)
He deliberately chose a single 1 Man wait?
Yagi has begun to break.
Ron.
Pinhu, one Dora.
Just then,
Akagi is starting to grasp the fundamental principles of competitive Mahjong.
Riichi.
Mahjong is not about how to win your own hands.
It is about how to deny your opponents theirs.
Only those who can expand their own vision can win.
Ron.
Mentanpin, 3 Dora.
It's over!
I'm sorry but I don't have the money on me right now.
Tomorrow I'll contact you.
Let's go home.
Yagi-san. It's not over yet.
Double or nothing with the three million we just won.
Now the game's wager is six million.
D-DOUBLE OR NOTHING!?
Akagi. Enough already!
I won't let it end here.
We keep going to the limit.
Until one of us falls apart.
AKAGI
Akagi,
Just do it another day.
Today is over.
It would be best to officially hold the rematch on another day.
I can ask a boss I know to supervise the match.
There's a lot of money at risk here.
That way there will be no tricks.
Heh. Don't worry about it kiddo.
The best stage for you to play on,
I will provide.
Ryuzaki. That's right, isn't it.
Agreed.
Akagi. You showed us some pretty interesting Mahjong.
Akagi.
Won't you think it over just once more?
Really, I...
It's enough that you've saved my life.
I don't want to get into a dangerous...
The contest is not over yet.
If that's the case, then at least
Just bet the three million we won today.
Just what we won.
If we bet my life again for 3 million my sanity can't take it.
That's fine.
At any rate,
It's best not to pay.
What intimidates them is our Madness.
The conviction to not apply the brakes.
And that time too I didn't brake at all.
Yeah, I thought that was the case.
I understand.
In that Chicken Run where you went off the cliff,
you had no intention of braking from the start.
And that's what saved you.
You thought that beforehand,
not to brake,
but rather the reverse, stepping on the accelerator.
That was your chance for victory, wasn't it.
You can't do something like that with only a chance of success.
Tonight's goal was only Nangou's.
W-what did I do?
Betting your life on a Mahjong game.
No one with an ordinary nerve could do that.
And that time,
"That time"?
You haven't forgotten, have you?
This was the first time I saw Nangou playing Mahjong.
When it was about to end,
That Sansyouku winning hand.
And that 5 Pin.
It was the most dangerous tile.
I'm gambling for fuck's sake.
That itself was just "stepping on the accelerator."
Not something that can be done with any normal nerve.
Trusting your soul to Madness.
Shall we see if we can avoid it one more time?
With Madness of the soul.
The madness of the soul?
Fujiya-san. It's been a long time.
8 Sou.
Fukumoto Sensei-->
Red Dragon.
That Yagi?
Yes. he's a wreck.
Playing a kid?
He's someone you easily take lightly.
He's involved with that crooked cop, Yasuoka.
It's very likely that Yasuoka
Is involved with the Nagauti gang.
So then our Miyoti group is involved
and we entrusted you with our power.
Fujiyosi
regarding the amazing master
That master is just now in a match.
3 Man!
Ron.
Chuuren Poutou. A Yakuman win.
Exactly eight million.
EIGHT MILLION!?
All I have to do is beat them.
Okay. I got it. We'll do it!
You little bastard!
Is this the end?
It's come.